Guide to the photograph album Tunisia Travel on the Kairouan AD.MC.043
Archives and Special Collections, New York University Abu Dhabi Library
A Trip to Tunisia on the Kairouan
Circa 1951
Archives and Special Collections, New York University Abu Dhabi Library
AD.MC.043
107 Photographic Prints 107 gelatin silver photographs contained within an album measuring 36 x 25 cm
.
Excellent condition. No tears or foxing.
Box 043
Arrangement
Collection processed as it was received.
Content Description
A travel album of Tunisia containing 107 gelatin silver photographs. The places visited are: Tunis, Carthage, Sidi Bou Said, Nabeul, Hammamet, Monastie, Mahdia, Sousse,El Djem, Gabes, Sfax, Matmatas, Douirot, Djerba, Gafsa, Medenine and Kairouan.
Tunisia; Architecture; Regional/National Dress; Photographic Prints
- The front cover of the album 'A Trip to Tunisia on the Kairouan.', Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref1; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Tunisia
- A map of Tunisia., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref2; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Maps; Tunisia
- The title page of the album 'A Trip to Tunisia on the Kairouan.' Beneath the title is a photograph of the ship Kairouan., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref3; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Boats/Ships; Tunisia; Transportation; French Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Water
- Group portraits of men and women on the deck of the Kairouan, with views of the ship setting sail from Marseille with the Palais du Pharo in the background., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref4; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; French Writing; Marseille, France; Men; Women; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Head Covers/Veils; Bags/Purses; Cameras; Group Portraits; Palaces; Buildings; Water; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Docks/Piers/Jetties
- Views of Tunisia taken from the ship labeled 'first contact (premier contact)' with a view of the Bay of Tunis., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref5; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Water; Women; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tunisia; Buildings; Boats/Ships; Transportation; French Writing; Men; Group Portraits; Newspaper Clippings; Streets/Roads; Cars/Trucks; Landscapes; Coast; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Newspapers/Magazines
- From the top-left clockwise: a view of the Bab el Bahr, the Arab district, and an aerial shot of Tunis., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref6; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Men; Group Portraits; Streets/Roads; Buildings; Doors/Entrances; Statues/Sculptures; Architecture; Landscapes; French Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tunis, Tunisia
- From left to right: two street views of men and women walking in Tunis, and a postcard of the Youssef Dey Mosque/Al B'chamqiya., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref7; Editions de luxe " Estel" Lavelle & Cie, Paris; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Women; Men; Streets/Roads; Regional/National Dress; Tunis, Tunisia; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Cars/Trucks; Transportation; Architecture; Mosques; Religious Sites; Head Covers/Veils; Postcards
- Postcards of the souk in Tunis., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref8; Editions de luxe " Estel" Lavelle & Cie, Paris; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Postcards; Men; Group Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Markets; Tunis, Tunisia; Shops; Facial Hair; Street Vendors; Workers; Streets/Roads; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; French Writing
- Three views of the Alaoui Museum in Bardo, and a group portrait of tourists walking through Tunis., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref9; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Palaces; Architecture; Buildings; Museums; Group Portraits; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Hats; Men; Women; Streets/Roads; French Writing; Bags/Purses; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Furnishings; Paintings; Tunis, Tunisia
- Clippings from printed material of the ancient port and Roman ruins in Carthage., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref10; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Water; Ports; Tunisia; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Newspaper Clippings; Newspapers/Magazines; Clouds
- From the top-left clockwise: An archaeological site undergoing excavation, remnants of Roman temples, a group of tourists, and two stelae in Carthage., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref11; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Women; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Bags/Purses; Hats; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Temples; French Writing; Tunisia
- Top and right: clippings of women and girls. Bottom and Left: Women and girls in Sidi Bou Said., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref12; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Women; Individual Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils; Girls; Children; Group Portraits; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Newspaper Clippings; Newspapers/Magazines; French Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tunisia; Jewelry; Postcards
- Views and clippings of potters and pottery in Nabeul, Tunisia., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref13; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Newspaper Clippings; Newspapers/Magazines; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Individual Portraits; Boys; Children; Pottery; Workers; Men; Women; Group Portraits; Buildings; French Writing; Facial Hair; Shops; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Nabeul‎, Tunisia
- From the top left clockwise: a portrait of stonemasons, children working on looms, a crowd at a carpet souk, and a doorway and a postcard of people at a market in a kasbah/ribat., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref14; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Carpets/Rugs; Workers; Shops; Postcards; Markets; Doors/Entrances; Pottery; Forts/Castles; Men; Group Portraits; Architecture; Buildings; Boys; Children; Nabeul‎, Tunisia; French Writing
- Left: a postcard of donkeys at a market. Right: a portrait of a man and a child riding donkeys., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref15; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Postcards; Donkeys; Animals; Men; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Markets; Tunisia; French Writing; Regional/National Dress; Boys; Children; Transportation; Streets/Roads; Facial Hair
- From the top left clockwise: a fishing net for Tuna, a newspaper clipping of a bride, and a wedding procession in Hammamet, Tunisia., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref16; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Newspaper Clippings; Newspapers/Magazines; French Writing; Fishing; Landscapes; Women; Weddings; Individual Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Men; Children; Boys; Group Portraits; Parades/Processions; Events/Occasions; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tunisia; Jewelry
- Portraits of people on the coast and the Ribat of Monastir, Tunisia., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref17; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Newspaper Clippings; Newspapers/Magazines; Tunisia; Boys; Children; Group Portraits; Water; Coast; Forts/Castles; Architecture; Women; Men; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Hats; Individual Portraits; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Docks/Piers/Jetties; French Writing
- From the top left clockwise: a postcard of ancient buildings, a portrait of a man leaning on a car, and a postcard of sardine boats in Mahdia, Tunisia., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref18; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Postcards; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cars/Trucks; Transportation; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Buildings; French Writing; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Boats/Ships; Men; Individual Portraits; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Water; Tunisia
- A postcard of the buildings in Sousse, and views of Habitat, Mahdia, and Kairouan Tunisia., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref19; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Landscapes; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Architecture; Water; French Writing; Tunisia
- From the left clockwise: a group of tourists on the beach, a group of boys, a portrait of a man and a woman on the roof of a car, and a man fixing an out-of-order vehicle in Sousse, Tunisia., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref20; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Men; Group Portraits; Hats; Beaches; Boys; Children; Streets/Roads; Cars/Trucks; Transportation; French Writing; Tunisia
- A page entitled 'The jobs of Tunisians (Les occupations des Tunisiens).' From the left clockwise: clippings of a woman begging, artisans making crafts, a postcard group of people, and a group at a restaurant (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref21; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Newspaper Clippings; Newspapers/Magazines; Individual Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Boys; Men; Children; Group Portraits; Workers; Head Covers/Veils; Women; Restaurants/bars; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Streets/Roads; Palm Trees; French Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tunisia; Postcards
- An aerial view of the Amphitheatre of El Djem., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref22; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Postcards; Newspaper Clippings; Newspapers/Magazines; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Landscapes; Tunisia; French Writing
- Interior and exterior views of the Amphitheatre of El Djem., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref23; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Tunisia; French Writing; Men; Individual Portraits
- Views of the oasis in Gabes, Tunisia., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref24; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Oases; Tunisia; French Writing; Women; Boys; Children; Group Portraits
- From the top left clockwise: a postcard palm trees in a desert, a clipping of a group of camels at a watering hole, and a portrait of a woman and a child., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref25; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Postcards; Newspaper Clippings; Newspapers/Magazines; Landscapes; Deserts; Clouds; Palm Trees; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Women; Boys; Children; Hats; Group Portraits; Tunisia; Oases; Camels; Animals
- Views of a body of water and palm trees., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref26; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Palm Trees; Water; Landscapes; Tunisia
- Views of a body of water and palm trees, one shows goats drinking from the water source., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref27; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Palm Trees; Water; Animals; Landscapes; Tunisia
- Views of the carriages and the road on the way to the oasis., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref28; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Horses; Animals; Streets/Roads; Group Portraits; Women; Men; Palm Trees; Tunisia; French Writing
- Views of men and animals operating water pumps/wells., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref29; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Newspaper Clippings; Newspapers/Magazines; Palm Trees; Irrigation; Machines; Agriculture/Farms; Men; Workers; Individual Portraits; Camels; Animals; Boys; Children; Group Portraits; Landscapes; French Writing; Tunisia; Water; Signatures
- Left: a postcard of a street view of Tunisia. Right: a postcard of people at a stream., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref30; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Postcards; Streets/Roads; Water; Men; Animals; Regional/National Dress; Buildings; Group Portraits; Palm Trees; Individual Portraits; Tunisia; Signatures
- Left: a newspaper clipping of men fishing for sponges in Sfax, Tunisia. Right: sponges on the coast., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref31; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Newspaper Clippings; Newspapers/Magazines; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Men; Group Portraits; French Writing; Tunisia
- Views of camels throughout tunisia., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref32; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Newspaper Clippings; Newspapers/Magazines; Camels; Animals; Men; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Mountains/Hills; Regional/National Dress; Tunisia; French Writing
- Left: a postcard of two men praying in the desert. Right: a view of the desert., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref33; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Postcards; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Regional/National Dress; Camels; Group Portraits; Landscapes; Animals; Praying; Tunisia
- Views of the Berber underground homes in Matmata., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref34; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; French Writing; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Houses; Palm Trees; Deserts; Landscapes; Tunisia
- From the top left clockwise: the entrance to the dwelling, a family living in the dwellings, a courtyard, the master bedroom, and a woman weaving on a loom., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref35; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; French Writing; Furnishings; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Houses; Men; Individual Portraits; Newspaper Clippings; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Workers; Tunisia
- Views of ruins in Douirat, Tunisia., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref36; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boys; Children; Regional/National Dress; Men; Group Portraits; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Tunisia; French Writing
- From the top left clockwise: a view of the desert on the way to Douirat, the Tomb of Marabou, and a clipping of a building on the way to Gabes., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref37; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Newspaper Clippings; Buildings; Architecture; Deserts; Mountains/Hills; Tunisia; French Writing; Tombs
- Group portraits of nomads., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref38; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Tents; Deserts; Women; Men; Regional/National Dress; Children; Boys; Girls; Camels; Mountains/Hills; Animals; Tunisia; French Writing
- Left: a postcard of a snake charmer surrounded by a crowd. Right: a postcard of people at a market., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref39; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Postcards; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Palm Trees; Men; Group Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Events/Occasions; Animals; Boys; Children; Women; French Writing; Markets
- From the top left clockwise: a group portrait of tourists on a boat, a boy in front of a buildings, a woman gathering well water, and a building on the island of Djerba., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref40; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Men; Women; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Smoking; Cigarettes; Group Portraits; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tunisia; Buildings; Architecture; Water; Head Covers/Veils; Regional/National Dress; Individual Portraits; Boys; Children; French Writing
- Two views of the El Ghriba synagogue and two views of a hotel for Jewish pilgrims on Djerba Island., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref41; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Men; Carpets/Rugs; Individual Portraits; Synagogues; Religious Sites; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; French Writing; Tunisia; Hotels; Women; Workers; Architecture
- From the top left clockwise: a couple, a group portrait in the oasis, a street scene, a Roman pool, and a minaret in Gafsa., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref41; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Men; Women; Streets/Roads; Buildings; Palm Trees; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Donkeys; Boys; Children; French Writing; Tunisia; Mosques
- Views of the ghorfas of Medenine, Tunisia., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref41; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Camels; Animals; Tunisia; Streets/Roads; Architecture; Buildings; French Writing
- Views of mosque architecture in the holy city of Kairouan, Tunisia., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref41; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Newspaper Clippings; Religious Sites; Newspapers/Magazines; Mosques; Men; Group Portraits; Architecture; French Writing
- Views of the Mosque Sidi Sahbi (Mosque of the Barbier) in Kairouan, Tunisia., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref41; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mosques; Religious Sites; Buildings; Architecture; Children; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Group Portraits; Men; Individual Portraits; Praying; French Writing; Tunisia; Religious Sites
- Two group portraits of tourists preparing for departure from Tunisia, and a view of Africa from the ship., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref41; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Women; Group Portraits; Cameras; Boats/Ships; Water; Transportation; French Writing; Tunisia; Hats; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses
- The inside back cover of the album 'A Trip to Tunisia on the Kairouan.', Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref41; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
- The back cover of the album 'A Trip to Tunisia on the Kairouan.', Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref41; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
- Left: a postcard of the oasis in Tozeur. Right: a clipping of a man next to a camel., Circa 1950s; AD_MC_043_ref41; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 043)
  Photographic Prints; Camels; Animals; Men; Group Portraits; Buildings; Palm Trees; Oases; Postcards; French Writing; Tunisia; Newspaper Clippings; Newspapers/Magazines